interaction-design.org 2017-06-14

# Personal Data Use and Privacy Policy | Interaction Design Foundation

The Interaction Design Foundation (“IDF”), a non-governmental, privately held organization located at Chr. Molbechs Vej 4, DK-8000, Aarhus C, Denmark, during the normal course of its activities, collects personal data about you and other users, for the purposes set forth in this Personal Data Use and Privacy Policy (hereinafter referred to as the “Privacy Policy”), by means of the website located at https://www.interaction-design.org (hereinafter, the “Site”) and/or other websites used and/or controlled by IDF from time to time. IDF does not collect more data than such personal data collected by analogous websites. Personal data collected by IDF is processed for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes, in accordance with applicable laws in Denmark. 

Personal data and any membership information provided by you to IDF when you enter and/or register into the Site will be used, among other purposes, to: (i) maintain a register of members and users; (ii) supply you with any goods and services you may request from IDF from time to time via the Site; (iii) creating browsing and consumption preferences profiles of you and other users in order to make them recommendations and provide them with links to certain goods and services; and (iv) creating databases to be used to send users e-mails with promotions, advertising and information of the Site. 

By entering, using and/or registering into the Site, you hereby provide IDF with your explicit consent for the collection, treatment and processing of your personal data according to this Privacy Policy. You, as the legitimate owner of your personal data, by using the Site hereby represent to be an adult to the date that the same is provided and to have full legal capacity in your jurisdiction. 

Edits, comments, commentaries and other contributions to the Site made or provided by you will be publicly distributed, and except in certain, very limited circumstances, will remain a permanent part of this site. If you decide to contribute to the Site, you must keep this in mind. Your contributions will be subject to the Site's [Terms and Conditions](https://www.interaction-design.org/index.php/about/terms-of-use) and IDF's [Site IP/Copyright Policy](https://www.interaction-design.org/index.php/about/copyright). 

Under "The Act on Processing of Personal Data", incorporated under Danish law, you may request a copy of the information we hold on you (for which we may request the applicable fee to offset our administration costs) by writing to our address first shown above or to the email legal@interaction-design.org. 

IDF has set up physical, technical and administrative security measures for the protection of your personal data. IDF shall undertake actions, measures and provisions it deems appropriate in order to safeguard its user's right to protect their personal data. As an example, IDF uses or implements the following measures, among others: (i) SSL encryption for the communication between your browser and IDF's servers; (ii) the highest form of server encryption available in the industry; (iii) 32 diesel-powered emergency generators with 2,250 kW capacity for N+2 redundancy, with 200,000 gallons of fuel on-site; (iv) redundant fire suppression and detection systems; (v) armed security around-the-clock; (vi) redundant geographically dispersed datacenters in case of terror attacks or nuclear explosions. IDF undertakes daily incremental backups and has 24/7/365 onsite management and surveillance. 

IDF will not share any email addresses of users, nor will it disclose any identifying personal data, to any third party, for any purpose whatsoever. Data collected by IDF through logging visits to the Site (e.g. originating IP, referral data, browser and platform type, traffic flows, geographical area of request) is only used in an aggregated, anonymous form, which means IDF will not make any further effort to personally identify its users. Collected data is only used for server administration, fault finding, site improvement and other legitimate purposes. 

Aggregate (and thus non-identifying) statistics generated from the Site may be reported as part of research results or may be published on the Site. 

For non-registered website visitors – as opposed to fully registered and paying members – IDF collects data commonly collected on most analogous websites (e.g. through Google Analytics or another analytics product). 

Any time you visit a page on the internet, you send information to a remote server. The servers that host the Site maintain access logs with the information that you send. This information is used to provide and generate statistics and analytics and to provide IDF with marketing and traffic data regarding the Site and other websites that link back to the Site. IDF does not intend to use these logs to identify legitimate users. 

The data logged may be used by IDF to solve technical problems with the Site and, in cases of abuse, to conduct any investigate therefrom. 

IDF may also use web analytics services to understand the type of traffic received by the Site and other of IDF's websites, in order to provide better services and to set benchmarks for IDF's goals. For example, through Google Analytics, the IDF records things like IP address, browsing time, length and date, sections visited, websites you accessed prior to the Site and type of browser. 

If you are concerned about attempts to match your IP address to your identity, you may wish to use an anonymous browsing service or attempt other means to obfuscate your real IP address. Browsing the Site does not reveal your identity publicly. 

Data collection for registered members is – by necessity – more extensive in order to allow the Site to function and operate with it. As an example, IDF records, including but not limited to, the following items: 

  * Complete name of the member.
  * E-mail address of the member.
  * Country of residence of the member.
  * Courses that the member is enrolled in.
  * Answers to questions in courses.
  * Local Groups the person has registered for.
  * IP address and country of each session (for security purposes).

Please be advised that part or all of this information will be shown on your “Public Profile page” as means of identification by other members and in order to generate engagement and participation by our community. IDF only publicly discloses data which is commonly and publicly available for most people through the Internet, such as name, profile picture, country and city of residence and links to personal social media pages and the website of each member. The disclosure of this information on your public profile page can be controlled by you at any moment. If you do not want to disclose it, please do not add it and select the necessary privacy settings in the Site and/or your social media pages. If you elect to delete part or all of your information by selecting the appropriate settings in the Site, such information will not be publicly shown through the Site. 

If you choose to cancel your membership, or if IDF terminates it, IDF will employ what is commonly referred to as a “soft delete” in its database, which means that data will still be stored physically in IDF's database but marked as “deleted”. IDF does so for the technical requirements of its relational databases and for dependent functionality such as the Local Group Rank and publications on the IDF Daily to continue to work. These functionalities depend on this data being available. 

If you forget to renew your membership, and hence it is auto-cancelled, the data marked as previously deleted (i.e. “soft deleted”) will be used to restore your course answers, local group affiliations, course certificates and other data if you elect to renew your membership at a later point. This will prevent a permanent loss of data for you. 

IDF will, of course, fulfill any request to permanently delete your data by means of an e-mail to legal@interaction-design.org. Such requests may take up to 6 weeks to process. 

All “Certification Pages” will remain publicly available after your membership is cancelled or terminated, including the profile information (e.g. name, picture, certifications) of the person having been certified. IDF undertakes this since a certification by the IDF entails a life-time certification. IDF will, of course, honor any request to permanently delete and stop public display of such data by means of an e-mail to legal@interaction-design.org. Such request may take up to 6 weeks to process. 

Company memberships (i.e. group memberships) also require the aforementioned data collection by IDF, so that it can be displayed to the pertinent company administrator (i.e. for evaluating employee compliance). 

With the purpose of providing a better experience to Users in the Website, IDF may use “cookies” or other kind of web beacons. This is often as a convenience for you to enable certain Site's features. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "cookies" shall mean text files of information sent by a website in your computer in order to store some records and preferences; and "web beacons" shall mean computer code inserted into a website or e-mail that can be used to monitor the behavior of a user (e.g. IP address, browsing time, length and date, sections visited, websites you accessed prior to the Site and type of browser). 

The Site may allow advertising or third party functions that send "cookies" to users. Through the use of "cookies", users are not personally identified, only their computers. 

Users may change their options through their computer equipment and/or browsers to stop accepting "cookies" and / or "web beacons" or confirm whether or not to accept them. 

You may wish to clear these cookies and the browser cache if you wish to refrain from revealing any identifying information, especially if you are using a public or shared computer. You may also prevent your browser from accepting cookies by disabling such functionality. 

IDF may use Google Analytics and other tools (like remarketing codes) from time to time to gather information about websites you browse view or when you undertake specific actions in a website. This allows IDF to provide targeted, customized advertising its audience. Thus, third party vendors (such as Google, Inc., Adroll, or Facebook) may show you IDF ads on certain websites across the Internet, even after you leave the Site. Such vendors may use cookies and other web beacons to track your Internet browsing in order to serve ads based on your past visits to the Site. 

The Site uses the Google AdWords remarketing service to advertise on third party websites (including www.google.com) to previous visitors to the Site. If you do not wish to receive this type of advertising from IDF now or in the future, you may opt-out by using the DoubleClick opt-out page (https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb%20/l%20display_optout) or the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page (http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). For Google-specific advertisement, You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Preferences page at http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/, and if you want to you can opt out of interest-based advertising entirely by cookie settings (see http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/) or permanently using a browser plugin like http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/intl/en/plugin/. 

In other words, IDF's ads do not collect any sensitive personal data about you. For purposes of these Terms, “sensitive personal data” shall mean your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade-union membership, data concerning health or sex life and financial data like credit card or bank information. 

If you wish to stop receiving messages via e-mail from IDF, simply click the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the e-mail. 

IDF may only release collected personal data under the following circumstances: 

  * As required by applicable law (e.g. in response to a valid request from a law enforcement agency).
  * To designated third parties, in order to resolve or investigate abuse complaints.
  * When the information is related to spiders, bots, and other technical issues.
  * When attempting to block abusive users or to complain to such ISP.
  * To defend itself or its affiliates from legal claims by third parties.
  * When deemed necessary to protect the rights of IDF's user community or the Site.

Any User of the Site can make a request to IDF in order exercise his rights to: 

  * Access his personal data.
  * Rectify his personal data when inaccurate or incomplete.
  * Cancel his personal data.
  * Object with legitimate reason the Process of his personal data.
  * Revoke his consent for the process of his personal data at any moment, in order to stop the use of the same.

The exercise of rights to access, rectify or cancel personal data and/or object or revoke consent should be requested in writing by users to IDF and must include at least the following: 

  * The data owner's name, address, and e-mail address to notify him of the response to his request.
  * Documents establishing the identity or, where appropriate, legal representation of the data owner.
  * A clear and precise description of the personal data with regard to which the data owner seeks to exercise any of the abovementioned rights (when rectification is requested, modifications that should be made should be specified and provide documentation to back up its request).

For the exercise of the previous rights, IDF hereby provides its users with the following e-mail address hello@interaction-design.org. 

The exercise of users of the abovementioned rights shall be subject to the laws and regulations applicable and in force in Denmark. 

When making contributions to the Site (e.g. posting a comment, commentaries, editing a page in the wiki), a name and email address may be required from a user. You do not have to use your real name, instead opting to use a pseudonym. You may also to get a free email account or attempt to use a remailing service when using the Site. 

Your activity on our Site may be identified by your IP address. These numbers could potentially be traceable to identifying information about you, whether it is your home ISP or the university or work account where the IP address is registered. 

If you are concerned about attempts to match your IP address to your identity, you may wish to use an anonymous browsing service or attempt some means to obfuscate your real IP address. If so, you may try to use Tor, an anonymous browsing service. 

The Site may include hyperlinks or hypertexts that, when used by users, may forward to other portals or Internet websites that may be property of third parties. Data provided by users through any of those portals or Internet websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy and are not the responsibility or liability of IDF. IDF encourages its users to verify the privacy notices displayed and applicable in those portals or Internet websites. 

Users may find within the Site, message boards, wikis, chat rooms, social media functionalities, blogs or other services that may be shared with third parties and that could collect your personal data (hereinafter the “Third Parties' Sites”). Any information related to your personal data provided through the Third Parties' Sites will be subject to the corresponding privacy notices contained in each one of them, unless IDF indicates otherwise. 

IDF shall not be liable for the use, publication, disclosure and/or reveal made from personal data used, published, disclosed and/or revealed through the abovementioned means. The content provided on the Site, including content posted by users, is for general information, discussion and entertainment purposes only. IDF makes no representations or guarantees about any aspect of any content on the Site and does not endorse any opinions expressed by any users. ALL CONTENT IS POSTED "AS IS" AND YOUR USE OR RELIANCE ON ANY CONTENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. IDF HEREBY DISCLAIMS ALL LIABILITY TO YOU FOR THE CONSEQUENCES OF USING OR RELYING ON ANY CONTENT IN OR WITHIN THE SITES. IDF DOES NOT WARRANTs OR GUARANTEEs THAT ANY INFORMATION AVAILABLE USING THE SITE OR OTHER SERVICES IS ACCURATE OR RELIABLE OR YOUR USE OF THE SITE WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, SECURE, OR FREE FROM ERROR. IDF, ITS VENDORS AND AFFILIATES GIVE NO EXPRESS WARRANTIES OR GUARANTEES NOR IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, WORKMANLIKE EFFORT, AND NON-INFRINGMENT. 

SOME STATES DO NOT ALLOW IDF TO LIMIT ITS LIABILITY FOR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES OR EXCLUDE CERTAIN WARRANTIES. IN THOSE STATES, IDF'S LIABILITY AND WARRANTIES ARE LIMITED TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW. 

IDF recommends its users to be careful and responsible on the personal information they provide through such means. 

IDF reserves the right to modify, at any moment, the terms of this Privacy Policy. Any change made to the Privacy Notice will be notified to users through the Site. Once a new version of the Privacy Policy is published, it will automatically be in force. 

Date of last revision is March 26th, 2016.
